-What happened?
-He's failing rapidly.
Has it happened before?
It's happened sometimes
since his organic functions are weak.
However, they say
it doesn't look good this time.
"It doesn't look good"?
What does that mean?
He might have to undergo surgery.
If he needs it, he should.
What are you waiting for?
Sang-gu.
Are you worried about the money?
I'll take care of it, so--
We haven't been able to stabilize him.
We wouldn't recommend the surgery
in his condition…
What's going to happen to him
if he doesn't get it?
Prepare yourselves to let him to go.
Fuck, no!
Let's get him that surgery.
-Sang-gu!
-Please.
You said he'd die if he doesn't get it.
We can't let him die without trying.
It's your call whether to proceed.
We'll only do what you wish us to do.
You need to discuss it yourselves,
and let us know.
We should stop here.
No way.
How much longer must Su-cheol and I suffer
just to make you feel at peace?
You've also seen what's going on here.
This is literally living in hell!
He's still alive.
He's held out for this long.
He still breathes, and his heart beats!
He won't die.
I won't let him.
Sang-gu!
I'm going to get the money
for his surgery.
Sang-gu!
Damn it.
No.
PROPERTY REGISTRATION CERTIFICATE
REGISTERED FOR HAN JEONG-U
REGISTRATION INFORMATION
THE LATE HAN JEONG-U
Now we're even, okay?
Why is he storming out at this hour?
As if he stole something
and ran away with it.
Where's your uncle?
He's out.
Geu-ru.
What do you think of your uncle?
He is
a filthy person.
He hates taking a shower
and cleaning the house.
He hates doing the laundry and dishes too.
He picks his nose and ears
and then wipes his finger on his shirt.
And he wears that same shirt for a week.
-Gross.
-And he is
a loud person.
Sorry?
He speaks loudly and yells a lot.
He also snores terribly when he sleeps.
He makes a lot of noise when he eats.
He burps after a meal.
I can hear him fart even in my room.
Okay, besides those nasty habits,
do you think he's good or evil?
Or do you find him unpleasant or scary?
Okay.
In that case, he is
a good person in a perplexing way.
What?
He always says bad things.
Like, "Blockhead! Nutjob."
"Don't make trouble.
Don't do anything stupid."
He's always snappy at me.
Right, but how does it
make him a good person?
But
he always helps me to do
what I want to do.
He found the yellow box in the dumpsite.
He also found the camera
in Ms. Lee's place.
Dad says what makes a good person is
how they try to understand others,
not how they talk.
Therefore,
Uncle is a good person
in a perplexing way.
10 YEARS AGO
Shit.
Bring it on!
You motherfucker!
Nightmare!
No need to count how much, right?
Hey.
Shit.
Freaking loser.
Wait, let me do it.
Gosh.
-Whoa.
-Get back here.
-Okay, brace yourself.
-Okay, ready?
Here we go.
Geez, man.
Get up, you punk.
Whoa, hey.
Get off me.
Shit.
You should've listened to me.
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
-What the fuck?
-Fucking moron.
Stay away, or I'll jump.
Why don't you, sissy?
If you jump,
I'll show your fucking ass respect.
-Jump.
-Little fucker.
What a moron.
He crossed it over.
-Hey, what are you doing to do?
-Go ahead.
What are you doing?
What?
Who are you?
It's not fucking your business.
Do you know us?
Of course, I don't.
Let's get to know each other.
What are you going to do?
Calling the cops on us?
Promise me
you don't touch that boy anymore,
then I'll walk away.
-Are you doped or something?
-What a nutjob.
Know your place.
What the…
You motherfucker.
Damn it!
Damn it.
-Shit.
-Hey.
Fuck.
If I twist it further,
you'll lose your arm.
I don't mind going to jail
for a few months for this,
but are you okay
with being crippled for life?
Please don't hurt me anymore.
Please.
You'll learn your lesson
once you lose one of your limbs.
-Stay still.
-Don't.
Did you just stop me?
These punks beat the hell out of you,
but you want me to stop?
They won't do that. If they do…
you can give them a lesson again.
Damn it.
Fuck!
Get lost, you punk.
-Let's go.
-Shit.
Thank you.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I don't like those bullies,
but I hate the ones even more
who get beaten up.
BOXING
Hey.
Take this.
I told you to stay away from me.
Please go.
You're really irritating!
Gosh!
Why did I help him the other night?
Geez.
It's on you.
I didn't ask for your help,
but you saved me anyway.
What the heck?
You got to be responsible
since you saved me the other night.
I was as good as dead,
but you brought me back to life.
So be responsible.
Why should I?
Are you crazy?
Get lost.
Go away!
Beat it, you punk!
Get out of my sight!
What a nutjob! Man.
Man, this little punk again.
Go away.
Get lost.
Shit, just go now!
Go away!
-Put them on.
-For real?
I'm not sure if they will fit.
It's perfect.
-See?
-With your long arms,
you can be an out-boxer.
"An out-boxer"?
You keep your opponent at a distance,
then finish him with one blow.
"With one blow."
Like this?
An out-boxer has a long reach,
but he must be freaking fast.
Like this.
-Give it a go.
-Wow.
Darn.
Put your guard up.
Extend your arm fast.
Wrap it around.
-And do that twice.
-Okay.
When you are done,
put it between your fingers.
Okay.
Go between the index finger and the thumb,
and wrap it around your wrist.
No. Bend your knees, you stupid.
Keep your guard up, okay? Again.
One, two. Step forward a bit more.
One, two!
Stretch your arm.
Use your hip. Keep your guard up.
Keep your hands up. Again.
Good! Keep it up! Don't give up!
One, two! Nice!
Don't touch the rope.
Use your knees more!
There you go! One, two!
Good job!
Make a last spurt!
We're not done yet. Go faster!
Let's Go!
Good! Till the end! Don't give up yet!
Su-jin, what are you doing here?
This is my sister.
Okay. Hi.
-This is my coach.
-Oh, I see.
Nice! Wonderful!
Here comes a punch. Good.
You dodge.
Hook! That's it!
You can't end up like me.
Let's go to a sport university
and to the national championships!
And why not be a national athlete too?
-Keep your distance.
-Round three.
-Good.
-Kim Su-cheol is
-the red, and the blue is…
-What's he doing?
-Man.
-Kim isn't doing good.
Su-cheol, don't get worked up. Stay calm.
-Okay, right hook!
-That's it.
-He gave a blow.
-Get in there.
-He keeps pushing.
-Good! Go!
-Right punch!
-Nice!
-One down.
-There you go!
Good! He's got one down!
-His strategy was good.
-That's right.
-Let's go.
-Kim is at an advantage.
We've worked hard for this.
-Using this chance, he should
-That's right.
-push him hard.
-Good.
-Time is almost up.
-Throw a counter now.
That's right! Beautiful!
-Kim got it!
-His right hook on the jaw was beautiful.
-Don't get up.
-The match is over.
Kim has won by a knockout.
-At the 94th national championships,
-He won!
Kim has made it to the top.
Kim Su-cheol is a winner!
You are the champion! Goodness!
He has been training hard…
That's right!
I trained that punk, you know?
Respect, Kim Su-cheol!
I need money.
REGISTRATION CERTIFICATE
Take it as collateral
and lend me money for surgery.
I need it now.
For surgery?
You mean you need money for Su-cheol?
You're something, you know that?
If his condition got worse to that point,
you should just thank him.
He's giving you a way out.
I don't need a way out.
There's a big match in a month.
Moneybags from overseas will come.
I won't fight anymore.
-You saw me on the ring.
-That's why I organized the event.
Everyone thinks
you're a washed-up fighter.
Did you forget already
what you did to me and Su-cheol?
I won't be played
by your little scheme again.
It's up to you.
You can get the money for the surgery
and for all your debts with this one game.
If you do well,
I'll give back this deed,
untouched.
HOSPITAL NOW! SU-JIN
You…
Su-jin!
Sang-gu.
I got the money.
Let's get him the surgery.
What are you doing? We need to hurry.
Get him the surgery now!
He's just…
gone.
No, he can't be.
No.
No!
Get up, you punk.
You can't die.
You're not allowed to die!
Sang-gu!
You said I own your life.
So please get up now.
Get up now, and keep your promise!
Get up.
-Su-cheol!
-Get up…
Su-cheol!
Su-cheol…
Come in. It's a bit messy, though.
Have a seat there. I'll go make some tea.
Thank you.
For what?
For never giving up on my brother.
What are you talking about?
If you hadn't insisted on
keeping him alive,
I would have given up long ago.
One day,
I had this thought.
Like, on the day of the accident,
it'd have been better if he just had died.
Su-jin.
I hated myself
for having that kind of thought,
and I hated Su-cheol
for making me think like that.
I was sorry for him
but I hated him too.
You should've blamed me.
It was all my fault.
But I realized today
that I'm glad
to stay by him even that way.
If I had given up on him early,
I wouldn't have forgiven myself.
I wonder why now, though.
Maybe he was
waiting for you.
Su-jin.
Do you mind
if I take care of Su-cheol's belongings?
THE 94TH NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIPS
BOXING ARENA
1ST PLACE WINNER KIM SU-CHEOL
My boy, I'm so proud of you!
It's perfect.
See?
THE 94TH KOREAN NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIPS
DONGSEONG UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
MEDICAL DIAGNOSIS
PATIENT: KIM SU-CHEOL
CHRONIC TRAUMATIC ENCEPHALOPATHY
What?
Sang-gu.
I decided to quit boxing.
Sorry for not telling you sooner.
Are you serious?
Yes. I'm thinking
to run a supply store with my dad.
Kim Su-cheol, manager of Cheoljin Supply.
That'll be on my business card.
I want to make my dad's dream come true
before it's too late.
I'll fill you in on the details later.
PUNCH DRUNK SYNDROME: CTE FOR BOXERS
BRAIN CELL DAMAGE FROM REPEATED BLOWS
Anyway,
you got a different opponent for tonight.
Suddenly?
You didn't say anything about it.
It's a big match. We need someone special.
So, who is he?
Does it matter?
Remember.
It's round seven.
You can finish it
neither before nor after.
A knock out at round seven.
Just do your thing as usual.
Today,
we have a new face for this special match.
A former national athlete,
a former WBO Junior Lightweight Champion.
Kim Su-cheol!
Shit.
What's going on? What are you doing here?
-I didn't know I'd be fighting you.
-Why are you here?
To make money for my new business.
Oh gosh.
-What are you doing?
-Fight!
Hey, will you fight already?
Shit.
Okay, throw a punch, then.
No way. I won't.
Just do it, you idiot.
No way. You do it first.
Hey, Kim Su-cheol.
Are you still that fucking stupid wimp?
Are you back to that loser
who got beaten up on that bridge?
-Don't.
-So what are you going to do?
A national athlete? A champion?
I can fucking eat you alive.
-Sang-gu!
-Hit me.
Give it a go.
Come on. Do it.
Hit me now!
Come on. Do it now.
You fucking wuss, is this all you got?
Come on in.
Good.
Nice!
Go!
Good!
Smash him!
Get him!
Fight back!
Get in there now!
What are you waiting for?
Sweetie.
I get why you're doing this,
but we'll all go down
unless you stick to the plan.
Especially him.
That champion kid you care about so much.
It's his chance
to make money for his retirement,
but he won't get a penny
if you screw this over.
If that happens, who should be blamed?
Me? Or you?
Tell me the truth.
You brought Su-cheol here
on purpose, didn't you?
Tell me.
Answer me, you bitch.
It doesn't matter now.
Think carefully.
What do you think
is the best present
you can give to that kid?
Oh no. It's round seven already.
I'll fight in the last game before I quit.
I'm thinking
to run a supply store with my dad.
Kim Su-cheol, manager of Cheoljin Supply.
That'll be on my business card.
Shit.
Don't get up.
Don't you get up!
Please don't get up.
Just do what I say!
Oh yeah!
Sang-gu!
Over here!
Sang-gu! It's me, your brother!
Sang-gu!
Jeong-u, don't go.
Please take me with you.
Sang-gu, I'll be back for you shortly.
Okay? I'll be back soon, Sang-gu.
Just wait a bit.
-Punk, beat it!
-Sang-gu!
Jeong-u!
Please take me with you.
Fucking brother, my ass.
I have no brother now!
Don't you dare call yourself that!
Su-cheol.
Su-cheol!
Su-cheol…
No…
HAN JEONG-U, TRAUMA CLEANER
SANG-GU'S OLDER BROTHER!
MAKE SURE THEY MEET!
Subtitle translation by: Jean S Kim